Guide to the Jeanne Audrey Powers Papers RL.10181
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jeanne Audrey Powers papers
1924-2015 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Powers, Jeanne Audrey
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
RL.10181
58 Linear Feet 111 boxes
Reverend Doctor Jeanne Audrey Powers is a retired prominent activist clergywoman who was one of the first women to be ordained in the United Methodist Church. She is a longtime advocate for ecumenism and inclusiveness within the church. She was the highest-ranking UM church official to come out as gay in 1995. The collection contains materials documenting Reverend Doctor Powers’ personal and professional lives including correspondence, writings, family history, education, committee work, sermons, travels and activism.
Collection Overview
The Jeanne Audrey Powers papers span the dates 1924-2015 and contain files documenting her personal and professional lives including correspondence, writings, family history, education, committee work, sermons, travels, and activism.
The collection is arranged into the following series: Professional Papers, Personal Papers, Print Material, and Re-Imagining Movement. The Professional Papers series contains the following subseries: Conferences/Workshops/Schools, Ecumenical and Interreligious Work, Correspondence and Writing, and Activism. A 2015 addition to the collection (2015-0177) is organized into the same four series.
Biographical Note
Jeanne Audrey Powers was born in 1932 and raised in Mankato, Minnesota. She graduated from Minnesota State University in 1954, and the Boston University School of Theology in 1958. Powers was one of the first women ordained at the Minnesota Annual Conference of the United Methodist Church in 1958. Among her leadership positions within the church, Rev. Dr. Powers served as associate general secretary of the General Commission on Christian Unity and Interreligious Concerns (GCCUIC). In 1972, she created the Committee on the Status and Role of Women. The group advocates for the full participation of women in the church. Powers was also heavily involved with the Reconciling Ministries Network. Founded in 1982, it “strives to transform the world by living out the Gospel’s teachings of grace, love, justice, and inclusion for all of God’s children.” The group seeks to assist Methodists of all sexual orientations in their religious experiences. Powers also helped organize the 1993 Re-Imagining Conference, which aimed to encourage all churches to address worldwide gender inequities. During Powers’ sermon at the Fourth National Convocation of Reconciling Congregations in 1995, she announced to the crowd that she had been a lesbian all of her life. She framed this as “an act of resistance to false teachings that have contributed to heresy and homophobia within the church itself.” She received support from the GCCUIC, but criticism from church conservatives, who tried to force her into retirement. In response, Powers issued a statement saying that she would not speak further about the matter, but also would not retire early.
Provenance
The Jeanne Audrey Powers papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2011-2015.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Civil rights -- Religious aspects -- Christianity -- History -- 20th century; Feminism -- Religious aspects -- Christianity; Goddess religion; Homosexuality -- Religious aspects -- Christianity; Institute on Religion and Democracy; Ecumenical movement; Lesbian activists -- United States; Lesbian feminism -- United States; Lesbianism -- Religious aspects; Mankato (Minn.); Methodist Church -- Sermons -- 20th century; Methodist Church -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Sexism in religion; Women and religion -- Methodist Church; Women in Christianity -- United States -- History; Women in the Methodist Church; Powers, Jeanne Audrey; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Re-imagining Community; Powers, Jeanne Audrey
- Professional Files, 1959-2011 and undated
  - Education, Conferences, and Workshops
    - Journey to Jerusalem: Southwest Texas Conference: United Methodist Women: Lenten Retreat - March 1987 (Box 1)
    - Light-Warm-Fill-Heal: Claremont '89 - 1989 (Box 1)
    - Light-Warm-Fill-Heal: Claremont '89 - 1989 (Box 1)
    - Workshops: Gainsville, FL District U.M. School of Enrichment - 1992 (Box 1)
    - Workshops: 'Making Your Church More Inclusive' RCP: Washington, DC - 1993 (Box 1)
    - Workshops: General Commission on Christian Unity and Interreligious Concerns: Gainsville, FL - February 1992 (Box 1)
    - Workshops: Joint Training Events - 1984-1992 (Box 1)
    - Mid-West Regional School - ca. 1992 (Box 1)
    - Midwest School of Christian Mission - June 1992 (Box 1)
    - Women-Church: Claiming Our Power: Mujer Iglesia: Reclamando Nuestro Poder - October 9-11, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Workshops: General Commission on Christian Unity and Interreligious Concerns: Gainsville, FL - 1992 (Box 2)
    - Workshops: Baptism, Eucharist, Ministry - Undated (Box 2)
    - Spirituality Workshops - Undated (Box 2)
    - North Carolina Council of Churches - 1994 (Box 2)
    - G-ETS Commencement 'Wounded Healer' - 1995 (Box 2)
    - The 'Witches' of Gelnhausen - ca. 1995 (Box 2)
    - Borsch - 1985-1986 (Box 2)
    - Boston University School of Theology - 1987-1990 (Box 2)
    - Group Process - 1976-1987 (Box 2)
    - Africa Trip: Study-Travel Seminar with American University - 1966 (Box 2)
    - Fosdick Presching Convocation, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Minnesota Conference - 1978-1982 (Box 3)
    - Minnesota Conference Correspondence - 1983-1985 (Box 3)
    - A Church is Born: A Musical Play - 1984 (Box 3)
    - Jurisdiction Elections: Strategy - 1980 (Box 3)
    - Jurisdiction Conference: Episcopal Candidates - 1988 (Box 3)
    - North Central Jurisdiction Confereince: De Kalb - 1988 (Box 4)
    - Committees, Methodist Church: Publicity and Correspondence - 1988 (Box 4)
    - General Conference - 1992 (Box 4)
    - Jurisdictional Conferences - 1992 (Box 4)
    - Past Minnesota Conference Nominations - 1980-1984 (Box 4)
    - Minnesota General Jurisdiction Conference - 1991-1992 (Box 4)
    - Genneral Conference (Caucus Types) - 1984 (Box 4)
    - General Conference - 1984 (Box 5)
    - NC Jurisdictional Conference - 1984 (Box 5)
    - General Conference: MFSA, Houston Dec., Good News, Perfect Love, Pacific Dec., Affirm - 1988 (Box 5)
    - General Conference - 1985-1988 (2 folders) (Box 5)
    - Jurisdictional Conference - 1976 (Box 6)
    - General Conference: Portland - 1976 (Box 6)
    - Minnesota General Conference - 1980 (Box 6)
    - NC Jurisdictional Conference and Bishop's Letters - 1980 (Box 6)
    - World Methodist Conference: Nairobi - 1986 (Box 6)
    - World Methodist Council: Worship Consultation: Nairobi - 1986 (Box 6)
    - Ordained Women's Conference: Dallas - 1979 (Box 7)
    - Clergywomen's Consultation: Glorieta, N. Mexico - 1983 (Box 7)
    - Clergywomen's Consultation: Great George, NS - 1987 (Box 7)
    - Clergywomen's Consultation: Atlanta - 1995 (Box 7)
    - Clergywomen's Consultation: St. Charles, Il - 1991 (Box 7)
    - Dallas 'Symposium' - 1975 (Box 8)
    - Ordained Women Consultation - Undated (Box 8)
    - Regional School: San Diego - 1973 (Box 8)
    - Wisconsin School of Christian Mission - 1973 (Box 8)
    - Nashville District and Program Council Directors - 1974 (Box 8)
    - Pacific and South West School of Christian Mission - 1977 (Box 8)
    - North Indiana School of Christian Mission: Miami: California: Jeanne Audrey Powers - 1977 (Box 8)
    - FLA Workshop - 1992 (Box 8)
    - Schools of Christian Mission - 1973/1974 (Box 8)
    - Iowa Pastor's School - 1973-1974 (Box 8)
    - ALA: West Florida United Methodist Women - 1980-1981 (Box 8)
    - Latin American Trip - 1968 (Box 8)
    - Methodist Clergywomen's Gathering - 1985-1990 (Box 9)
    - National Consultation: Spirituality for Justice and Peace - November 26-30, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Rituals (Alternate Rituals Committee): Ritual In A New Day: An Invitation: JAP - 1973-1978 (Box 9)
    - General Conference (Caucus Types) - 1996 (Box 9)
    - General Conference - 1996 (Box 9)
    - Michael Kinnamon: Ecumenical Shared Ministry (ESM) Conference: Canada - 1993 (Box 10)
    - Ghost Ranch Holy Week Retreat - 1995 (Box 10)
    - Holocaust Conferences - 1995-2003 (Box 10)
    - International Association Women Ministers (IAWM): Misc international contacts, organizations - 1985-2011 (Box 10)
    - Riverside Church: Fosdick Convocation - 1997 (Box 10)
    - San Diego Clergywomen's Convocation - 2001 (Box 10)
    - NCC/Nationall Workshop of Christian Unity: Pittsburgh, PA - 2011 (Box 10)
    - WCC Worship - 1971 1991 (Box 10)
    - NCC (Faith Order) - 1976-1981 (Box 10)
    - World Council of Churches Ecumenical Decade - November 1998 (Box 10)
    - National Council of Churches (USA) - 1983-1995 (Box 11)
    - National Council of Churches Inclusive Language Lectionary Project - 1978 (Box 11)
    - Riverside Church: Hymnal Comm - 1978-1981 (Box 11)
    - World Student Christian Federation Book - 2008-2009 (Box 11)
    - Gathering: JA Powers Participated - 1965-1967 (Box 11)
    - The Claremont Seminary Story - 1995-2008 (Box 11)
    - Board of Higher Education Ministry (UMC) - 1989-1993 (Box 11)
    - MN Conference - 1976-2011 (Box 11)
    - MN Annual Conf - 2010 (Box 11)
    - Women the Bible: School of Missions 77: Christian United Methodist Women - 1977 (Box 11)
    - Minnesota Conference Correspondence - 1987-1995 (Box 12)
    - (UMC) Minnesota Conference '09 - 2009 (Box 12)
    - Minnesota Conference: Communication - 1998-1999 (Box 12)
    - Minnesota Conference: Order of Elders - 1998-2002 (Box 12)
    - Quaker Work Camp: Mexico - 1955 (Box 12)
    - Methodist Student Movement: Urbana, IL - 1961 (Box 12)
    - Methodist Student Movement: Lawrence, Kansas - 1953-1954 (Box 12)
    - Riverside Church Worship Committee - 1970-1994 (Box 11)
    - National Student Christian Federation (NSCF): Athens, OH - 1959-1960 (Box 12)
    - Association of College University Ministers (ACUM) - 1962 (Box 12)
    - World Student Christian Federation (WSCF): Quebec - 1963 (Box 12)
    - Methodist Student Movement (MSM): Ottio - 1963 (Box 12)
    - Methodist Student Movement (MSM): Poinsett - 1964 (Box 13)
    - National Convocation of Methodist Youth: W. Lafayette, IN - 1964 (Box 13)
    - North Central Methodist Student Movement (NCMSM): Poinsett - 1962-1963 (Box 13)
    - General/Jurisdictional UMC Conference: Women's Caucus - 1992 (Box 13)
    - North Central Women's Caucus: Jurisdictional Elections - 1996 (Box 13)
    - UMC Annual Conferences: Reaction to GLBT Issue - 1978-2001 (Box 14)
    - UMC Women's Caucus - 1986 (Box 14)
    - Baptism Task Force: Judicial Council Ruling - 1991-1999 (Box 14)
    - Baptism Task Force - 1999, 2000-2002 (Box 14)
    - School of Christian Missions (WSCS) (Powers Teaching) - 1965 (Box 14)
    - UMC Women's Division: School of Christian Mission Class - 1970-1977 (Box 15)
    - Baptism Task Force: 2nd Round for General Conference - 2004 (Box 15)
    - Baptism Training for 2004 Gen. Conf. (Box 15)
    - Beijing World Conference - 1995 (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches Offical Docs - 1997-1998 (Box 15)
    - Information From World Council of Churches - 1996-1998 (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches Delegates - 1998 (Box 15)
    - Reporting on World Council of Churches - 1997-1999 (Box 15)
    - World Council of Churches Informational Papers - 1998-1999 (Box 15)
    - Jubilee (Newspaper of World Council of Churches) - 1998 (Box 15)
    - General Conference - 2008 (Box 16)
    - Minnesota Conference 'Christian Conferencing' (GLBT Petitions for General Conference '08) (Box 16)
    - Minnesota Annual Conference 2009: General Conference Amendments (Box 16)
    - UMC Minnesota Conference, Misc - 2009 (Box 16)
    - Minnesota Conference Ministries Network - 1998-2008 (Box 16)
    - General Conference re Reconciling - Undated (Box 16)
    - Post-General Conference (Reconciling Ministrities Network) - 2000 (Box 16)
    - Reconciling Ministries Network General Conference: 2000 Preparations (Box 16)
    - Materials: General Conference - 2000 (Box 16)
    - 2004 General Conference: Press Responses (Box 17)
    - General Conference 2004: UMC - 2004 (Box 17)
    - Minnesota Conference: GLBT Strategy - 2004 (Box 17)
    - Reconciling Ministries Network General Conference - 1996 (Box 17)
    - World Council of Churches Urban Rural Mission: Zimbabwe - 1998 (Box 17)
    - Pre-General Conference - 2000 (Box 17)
    - Eighth Assembly: World Council of Churches: Harare, Zimbabwe - December 1998 (Box 17)
    - World Council of Churches 40th - 1988 (Box 18)
    - World Council of Churches - 1991-1998 (Box 18)
    - United Methodists Open The Doors...To All Persons Regardless of Sexual Orientation: The Organizing Packet: Reconciling Congregation Program - 1996 (Box 18)
    - Reconciling Congregation Program - 1998 (Box 18)
    - Witness Our Welcome 2000s: God's Promise Is For You! - WOW! 2000 - a gathering of Welcoming Churches and their allies in the United States and Canada: August 3-6, 2000: Northern Illinois University: DeKalb, Illinois: Program Book (Box 18)
    - The Fifth National Convocation of Reconciling Congregations and Campus Ministries: Come to the Table: July 24-27, 1997: Emory University, Atlanta (Box 18)
    - The Sixth National Convocation of the Reconciling Congregation Program: Proclaiming Jubilee: Renew Release Reconcile Rejoice: July 29-August 1, 1999: University of Texas: Denton, Texas (Box 18)
    - WOW! 2003: Witness Our Welcome 2003: August 14-17, 2003: University of Pennsylvania: Philadelphia, PA: God's Deliverance is for All! (Box 18)
    - Reconciling Ministries Network Convocation 2001: Revival! (Box 18)
    - A Reconciling Cookbook: Recipes for an Inclusive Church: A Handbook of Activities and Strategies for the Reconciling Congregation Program's General Conference Campaign - Undated (Box 18)
    - Student Recognition Brochure by JAP - 1967 (Box 18)
    - Minnesota Wesley Foundation - 1959-1968 (Box 19)
    - World Student Christian Federation - 1990 (Box 19)
    - St Paul Wesley Foundation - 1964-2002 (Box 19)
    - Wesley Foundation Alumni - 1955-2003 (Box 19)
    - Awards: Anna Howard Shaw Carter: Pioneer Woman Award Event - 1995 (Box 19)
    - Minnesota Foundation for Social Action Ball Affirmation Wheatley Awards: General Conference - 1996 (Box 19)
    - Anna Howard Shaw Center: Board Member Information - 1998 (Box 19)
    - Awards, Misc. - 1993-2008 (Box 19)
    - Jeanne Audrey Powers Honorary Doctorate - 1984 (Box 19)
    - The Jeanne Audrey Powers Ecumenical Award - 1996-1997 (Box 19)
    - Anna Howard Shaw Center - 1995 (Box 20)
    - Anna Howard Shaw - 1995-1998 (Box 20)
    - Awards: Minnesota Women's Press - 1996 (Box 20)
    - Saint of Cambridge: Welcoming Ministries - 2000-2002 (Box 20)
    - Mission Evangelism: WCC - 1989-1994 (Box 20)
    - England Sabbatical - 1976 (Box 20)
    - Divorce Conference Materials - 1971-1979 (Box 9)
    - North Central Methodist Student Movement (NCMSM): Lincoln, NE - 1964-1965 (Box 13)
    - North Central Women's Caucus - 1996-1998 (Box 14)
    - Riverside Church - 1980-2009 (Box 20)
    - Riverside Convocation: Homophobia - 1987 (Box 20)
    - Auburn: Feminist Theology Conference - 1997 (Box 20)
    - Philadelphia WCC Conference - 1986 (Box 20)
    - Kairos Comotion - 1995-2002 (Box 96)
    - Lists: Old - 1988-2000 (Box 96)
    - Lists, People - 1969-1992 (Box 96)
    - Events, Misc - 1993-1998 (Box 96)
    - Obama Inauguration - 2009 (Box 96)
  - Ecumenical and Interreligious Work
    Scope and Contents
    Contains materials related to Powers' seminary work, sermons and documentation of her involvement in interreligious and interdenominational activites. Also contains materials relating to her chapter in the 2003 Sara Evans book: Journeys that Opened Up the World.
    - Baptism, Eucharist, Ministry - 1976-1990 (Box 21)
    - Presbyterian Church: Reports to the 203rd General Assembly: Part 1 - June 1991 (Box 21)
    - Language - ca. 1988 (Box 21)
    - Biblical Translations - ca. 1982 (Box 21)
    - Hennepin Sermon Prep - 1995 (Box 21)
    - Sermons, etc. by JAP - ca. 1990s (Box 21)
    - Seminar Briefings - ca. 1970s (Box 21)
    - Bible Study: NWCU: (Powers-Welsch): Disciples Convention: JAP - 1977 (Box 22)
    - Disciples Convention: JAP - 1977 (Box 22)
    - Minn. Conf. Sermon (and Related Materials): Week of Prayer - 1987-1991 (Box 22)
    - Hennepin Ave. UMC Sermon - 1996 (Box 22)
    - Garrett-Evangelical Theological Seminary: Interview - 1982 (Box 22)
    - Journey in the Power of the Spirit: Clergy Women's Consultation - 1979 (Box 22)
    - Mankato, MN - 1977 (Box 22)
    - Shared-Facilities: The Mankato Center - 1977, 4 folders (Box 22)
    - Methodism Eucharist Wesley - 1979-1988 (Box 22)
    - A Descriptive Study of the Curriculum in the Field of Religion and Education Offered at Selected Theological Institutions in Canada and the United States - 1986 (Box 22)
    - The Ecumenical Institute: Chicago - 1969 (Box 22)
    - Religious Services - 1976-1991 (Box 23)
    - Christian Women - 1964-1995 (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous - 1976-1988 (Box 23)
    - Miscellaneous Instructional Docs - 1986 (Box 23)
    - Ecumenical Papers - 1979-1994 (5 folders) (Box 23)
    - Interfaith Papers - 1978-1994 (Box 24)
    - Marjorie Matthews - 1980 (Box 24)
    - Oxford Institute - 1992 (Box 24)
    - Oxford Theological Institute - 1973 (Box 24)
    - Louisvile: U.M.W. - 1978 (Box 24)
    - Rituals: Miscellaneous - 1968-1982 (Box 25)
    - David Randolph Project: Miscellaneous Material - 1970-1976 (Box 25)
    - Rituals: Next Steps - 1972-1983 (Box 25)
    - Ritual in a New Day (Media Coverage) - 1976-1978 (Box 25)
    - Assembly Worship - 1991 (Box 25)
    - Ministry Study - 1984-1988 (Box 26)
    - Global Nature of the Church (JAP) - 1980-1995 (Box 26)
    - United Methodist Women's History - 1968-1991 (Box 26)
    - Executive Staff - 1973-1996 (Box 26)
    - Support Staff - 1976-1994 (Box 26)
    - Academic Affairs: G-ETS - 1992-1996 (Box 26)
    - Garrett: ETS - 1982-1996 (Box 27)
    - Return to Jeanne Audrey Powers: GETS - 1991-1996 (Box 27)
    - Order of St. Luke - 1964-1995 (Box 27)
    - Auburn - ca. 1996 (Box 27)
    - Charles Wesley Society - 1976-1993 (Box 27)
    - Tom Oden Matters (JAP) - ca. 1994 (Box 27)
    - Bible Studies: Women - 1982-1991 (Box 27)
    - Bible Study/W.C.C. (Worship Mexican Notes) (Canaanite Woman) - ca. 1985 (Box 27)
    - Bossey - 1997-2004 (Box 28)
    - CORLE: Commission on Regional Local Ecumenism - 1976 (Box 28)
    - Consultation on Church Union - 1982-2002 (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Coworkers, Employees - ca. 1991 (Box 28)
    - Ecumenical Decade Churches: Women - 1993-2000 (Box 28)
    - Ecumenical Decade: Churches in Solidarity with Women - 1992-1998 (Box 28)
    - The Ecumenical Scene: Key Papers - 1978-1997 (Box 28)
    - Ecumenical Shared Ministry (GCCUIC) - 1993 (Box 29)
    - Ecumenical Shared Ministries - 1995-2000 (Box 29)
    - Mission Papers - 1968-1982 (Box 29)
    - Oxford Theological Inst. - 1992 (Box 29)
    - 'Journeys...' Book Computer Disk - 2001-2002 (Box 29)
    - 'Journeys...' Book Correspondence - 1996-2005 (Box 29)
    - 'Journeys...' Book Info/Marketing/Promo - 2003-2004 (Box 29)
    - 'Journeys...' Book: JA Powers Chapter Copies - Undated (Box 29)
    - 'Journeys...' Book: JA Powers Chapter Earlier Drafts - 1999-2003 (Box 29)
    - 'Journeys...' Book: Other Chapters - 1997-1999 (Box 30)
    - 'Journeys...' Book: Additional Notes - 1995-2001 (Box 30)
    - JA Powers Writing Published - 1967 (Box 30)
    - Misc: Prayers: Written by JA Powers - 1959-2009 (Box 30)
    - Notes for Sermons Speeches - Undated (Box 30)
    - Programs and Services: JAP - 1972-1992 (Box 30)
    - Misc Speeches - Undated (Box 30)
    - Jeanne Audrey Powers: Sermons on Sexuality - 1962-1963 (Box 30)
    - Sermons by JA Powers: 'Between the Tower the Table' MN Annual Conference - 1987 (Box 30)
    - Religion the Feminist Movement: JA Powers' Speech - 2002 (Box 30)
    - Eucharistic Services Development - Undated (Box 30)
    - Evolving Worship - 1971-1998 (Box 31)
    - The Creation of Worship and Tools for JA Powers' Teaching - 1963-2009 (Box 31)
    - JA Powers New Worship Paradigm - 1966-2009 (Box 31)
    - The Development of Worship in the Liturgical Revival - 1960s-1970s (Box 31)
    - Worship: Faith Life Community - 1962 (Box 31)
    - Beaumont's '20th Century Folk Mass' and 'Jazz in the Church' - 1960-1969 (Box 32)
    - Church Services: Special Occasion - 1965-2004 (Box 32)
    - Sermons - 1967-1981 (Box 32)
    - 1776 Bicentennial Sermons - 1974-1976 (Box 32)
    - Worship Materials - 1962-1991 (Box 32)
    - Various Wesleyan Services - 1957-1991 (Box 32)
    - Passover Seder - 1972 (Box 32)
    - Litanies: Acts of Worship - 1958-1981 (Box 32)
    - Baptism, Eucharist, Ministry - 1991-1996 (Box 32)
    - Bible Study Materials (Group) - 1960-1978 (Box 32)
    - Biblical Characters - 1983-2006 (Box 32)
    - Denominational Ecumenism - 1997 (Box 32)
    - Devotions - 1981-1996 (Box 32)
    - Easter Week - 1997 (Box 32)
    - Ecumenism - 1982-2010 (Box 32)
    - Eucharist - 1985-2001 (Box 32)
    - Charles Wesley Society - 2000-2011 (Box 33)
    - Ecumenical Articles Saved by U. Methodists - 1970s (Box 33)
    - Holy Living, Holy Dying - Undated (Box 33)
    - Methodist Archives - 1983-1984 (Box 33)
    - Methodist Changes Bishop Elections - 1975-2000 (Box 33)
    - Methodist History - 1968-2010 (Box 33)
    - Methodist Board of Mission History - 1961-1966 (Box 33)
    - Methodist/Lutheran Dialogue - 2009 (Box 33)
    - Methodist Student Movement - 2009 (Box 33)
    - Methodist: Ordination of Women - 1996 (Box 33)
    - Methodist Women - 1996 (Box 33)
    - UFMCC Unsuccessful Bid for NCCC Membership (UM History) - Undated (Box 33)
    - Baptist Students in Industry - 1956 (Box 34)
    - Summer Evangelist - 1957-1958 (Box 34)
    - Ecumenical Institute: Switzerland - 1958-1959 (Box 34)
    - The (Chicago) Ecumenical Institute - Summer 1967 (Box 34)
    - Global Nature of the Methodist Church - 1995-1998 (Box 35)
    - JA Powers' Teaching Course on Ecumenism - 1981-1992 (Box 35)
    - Local Church Training Materials - 1992 (Box 35)
    - UMC/Creating Contemporary Hymnody - 1960s (Box 35)
    - UMC 'New Hymnal' - 1964 (Box 35)
    - UMC Foundation - 2008 (Box 35)
    - United Methodist Women - 1998-2002 (Box 35)
    - Baptism - 1966-2008 (Box 35)
    - Sermons by Others - 1965-2008 (Box 36)
    - Cuban Seminary - 2006-2009 (Box 36)
    - Ecumenical Articles - 1992-1998 (Box 36)
    - Films Theology - 1992 (Box 36)
    - Humor: Writing, Cartoons, etc. (by Others) - 1987-2008 (Box 36)
    - Solstice - 1998-2009 (Box 36)
    - Spirituality - 1985-1986 (Box 36)
    - Thanksgiving - 1966 (Box 36)
    - Theology - 1960-2000 (Box 36)
    - Baptism Advisory Team - 1998-2000 (Box 36)
    - Ecum. Actions Team: Minn. Conf. - 1998-2000 (Box 36)
    - Global Church - 1963-1999 (Box 36)
    - Sermon by JA Powers: US2S - 1969 (Box 36)
    - Steve Fink Scholarship by JA Powers - 1987-2011 (Box 36)
    - Baptism - 1995 (Box 37)
    - Baptism/Confirmation Worship - 1969-2002 (Box 37)
    - Baptism, Eucharist, Ministry (BEM) - 1989 (Box 37)